<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Lenz Zuber</title><link>https://lezuber.com/</link><description>Recent content on Lenz Zuber</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lezuber.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Supercharge your Journal using Backlinks</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/supercharge-your-journal-using-backlinks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/supercharge-your-journal-using-backlinks/</guid><description>Before you start, take a short moment to ponder about the way your very own brain connects memories.
How does your brain connect memories? Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m often surprised about the weirdness of jumps my mind does between seemingly completely unrelated areas.
Yesterday, for example, I was chatting with my friend Peter about challenges in math education in elementary school. Suddenly, I wanted to talk about a guy we met at dinner the other day.</description></item><item><title>🌳 Evergreen Note</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/evergreen-note/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/evergreen-note/</guid><description>Taking smart notes while consuming any type of media into 📚 Literature Notes is an already great habit to increase comprehension and recall. But to level up even further, it can be of great value to make a habit out of extracting ones very personal, key insights into short, atomic notes about one single thing. It&amp;rsquo;s important to be as narrow as possible, while still capturing the entirety of the thing.</description></item><item><title>Atomicity of Evergreen Notes</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/atomicity-of-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/atomicity-of-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>Atomicity describes the objective to be as narrow as possible, while still capturing the entirety of the thing. The atomicity of an evergreen note is the key requirement to allow effective linking between them.
Questions Why is atomicity crucial for the effectiveness evergreen notes? #card
Atomicity describes the objective to be as narrow as possible, while still capturing the entirety of the thing. The atomicity of an evergreen note is the key requirement to allow effective linking between them.</description></item><item><title>Hi there!</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/hi-there/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/hi-there/</guid><description>I have no idea how you have found your way to this mostly empty, but beautiful, place! Recently, I discovered this beautiful Logseq-Plugin logseq-schrodinger which converts my Knowledge Graph into a beautiful Hugo Website using this beautiful template.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided yet, which pages I would like to publish and which not. Lets see how it goes! To start, checkout Zettelkasten Method.</description></item><item><title>Bidirectional Links</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/bidirectional-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/bidirectional-links/</guid><description>A bi-directional link has social awareness - it knows about other pages or &amp;rsquo;nodes&amp;rsquo; that point to it, and can make them visible on both sides of the link. This turns out to be an extremely powerful tool in PKM-Systems to navigate to ones Knowledge Garden.
Implicit Notes by Backlinking is supercharging this ability even further, by creating nodes in the Knowledge Graph even when they have no content yet. Then, they are &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; a overview of all backlinks referring to this page.</description></item><item><title>Contextual backlinks</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/contextual-backlinks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/contextual-backlinks/</guid><description>A contextual backlink displays not only a reference from another location, but the specific context around that reference - for instance, the page of a book or the referencing paragraph. That way it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to grasp why a link has been created without following the link right away.
One problem with this feature is, that this discourages clever ways of linking notes which explicitly state why the connection is meaningful.</description></item><item><title>Implicit Notes by Backlinking</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/implicit-notes-by-backlinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/implicit-notes-by-backlinking/</guid><description>A very powerful technique to organise the knowledge is to steadily create backlinks to nodes which don&amp;rsquo;t even exist yet. This can include things like Persons, Places, Movies, Concepts, and many more. By using the same backlinks in many different occurrences, the node becomes defined implicitly.
This effect requires Contextual backlinks, a simple list of backlinks won’t implicitly define a node very effectively. You need to be able to see the context around the backlink to understand what’s being implied.</description></item><item><title>Logseq</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/logseq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/logseq/</guid><description>Logseq is one of the most powerful PKM Tools out there. My blog is generated out of my fork of logseq-graph using logseq-schrodinger.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten Method</title><link>https://lezuber.com/pages/zettelkasten-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.com/pages/zettelkasten-method/</guid><description>Your brain does not sort knowledge in a hierarchy like folders or categories. It&amp;rsquo;s much more fluid. It creates links between individual, atomic thoughts like memories, ideas and concepts. These links are very powerful to jump between very different areas of your memory. What if we could replicate this linking in our notes as well - creating your second brain that works just like your main one, like a friend helping you to organise your thoughts.</description></item></channel></rss>