<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>🌳 Evergreen on Lenz Zuber</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/tags/evergreen/</link><description>Recent content in 🌳 Evergreen on Lenz Zuber</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lezuber.github.io/tags/evergreen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bidirectional Links</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/bidirectional-links/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/bidirectional-links/</guid><description>A bi-directional link has social awareness - it knows about other pages or &amp;rsquo;nodes&amp;rsquo; that point to it, and can make them visible on both sides of the link. This turns out to be an extremely powerful tool in PKM-Systems to navigate to ones Knowledge Garden.
Implicit Nodes by Backlinking is supercharging this ability even further, by creating nodes in the Knowledge Graph even when they have no content yet. Then, they are &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; a overview of all backlinks referring to this page.</description></item><item><title>Contextual backlinks</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/contextual-backlinks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/contextual-backlinks/</guid><description>A contextual backlink displays not only a reference from another location, but the specific context around that reference - for instance, the page of a book or the referencing paragraph.</description></item><item><title>Implicit Nodes by Backlinking</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/implicit-nodes-by-backlinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/implicit-nodes-by-backlinking/</guid><description>A very powerful technique to organise the knowledge is to steadily create backlinks to nodes which don&amp;rsquo;t even exist yet. This can include things like Persons, Places, Movies, Concepts, and many more. By using the same backlinks in many different occurrences, the node becomes defined implicitly.
This effect requires Contextual backlinks, a simple list of backlinks won’t implicitly define a node very effectively. You need to be able to see the context around the backlink to understand what’s being implied.</description></item><item><title>Backlinks - Harmful or helpful</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/backlinks-harmful-or-helpful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/backlinks-harmful-or-helpful/</guid><description>Every linking between notes adds a choice to the future you of additional notes to discover when stumbling over an evergreen note. So, each of this choices has an opportunity cost, as all linked notes compete for your attention in a world of limited time.
For that reason, one should always make sure that a given link adds real value to the reader. However, an automatically generated backlink does not necessarily add the same value as the original link.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten Method</title><link>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/zettelkasten-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lezuber.github.io/pages/zettelkasten-method/</guid><description>The Zettelkasten, coined by Niklas Luhmann, is a note-taking method to transform information of any source into a personal, lifetime knowledge graph.
As an inspirational example, at one point in his life he was offered a full professorship position as a result of his impressive work to that date. The only problem: he neither had a PhD nor Habilitation. So, he wrote both in less than a year! How could he be so productive?</description></item></channel></rss>